Guide to the Boyd McDonald papers, 1925-1993.
McDonald, Boyd papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Boyd McDonald papers, 1925-1993.
7782
McDonald, Boyd
14.5 cubic ft.
Photographs, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Files relating to Boyd's and others' work with "The Guide: Gay travel, entertainment, politics, & sex," "Alibi," and ""Straight to Hell: The Manhattan Review of Unnatural Acts."
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Boyd McDonald was a writer and anthologist who started "Straight to Hell: The Manhattan Review of Unnatural Acts" and compiled about a dozen subsequent anthologies based on true-life stories of gay men's sexual experiences. He was involved in the publication of Boston-based "The Guide: Gay travel, entertainment, politics, & sex" and "Alibi."
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Files relating to Boyd's and others' work with "The Guide: Gay travel, entertainment, politics, & sex," "Alibi," and ""Straight to Hell: The Manhattan Review of Unnatural Acts," including the photo archives and correspondence of "The Guide" and "Alibi," 1988-2003.
SUBJECTS
Names:
McDonald, Boyd
Titles:
The Guide: Gay travel, entertainment, politics, & sex.; Scum.
Subjects:
Gay liberation movement.; Erotica.; Pornography.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Collecting program: Human Sexuality Collection.
Related collection: The William Andriette Papers, #7725, include a video interview with Boyd McDonald.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
The records are arranged in three series: I. Photographs; II. Correspondence; III. Computer files.
The arrangement is roughly chronological.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Photographs
Boxes 1-6
Series II. Correspondence
Boxes 7-14
Series III. Computer files
Box 15
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Photographs
  - Photos, July 1988 - June 1991 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous information, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - Photos, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - "Fotos", 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Alibi Fotos, May 1993 (Box 4)
  - Fotos, July - November 1994 (Box 5)
  - Alibi, January - December 1995 (Box 5)
  - The Guide Photo Archive (Box 6)
  - Scum Photos (Box 6)
    1 folder
- Series II. Correspondence
  - The Guide correspondence, 1990s (Box 7)
  - F. Wall, Guide correspondence, mid 1990s - 2003 (Box 8)
  - Alibi, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous ads, 1991-1993 (Box 9)
  - Alibi, 1994, 1997 (Box 10)
  - Alibi files, 1996 (Box 11)
  - Records, 2001 (Box 12)
  - Guide & Alibi, ca. 2001-2003 (Box 13)
    Lawsuits
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, The Guide (Box 15)
- Series III. Computer files
  - Digital guide issue backups and correspondence, ca. 1990-1996 (Box 15)
    3.5", Zip, and Jaz, disks.
SEPARATED MATERIAL
The issues of the publications have been catalogued individually.